Guide to the Anne LaBastille papers, 1963-2004
LaBastille, Anne papers,1963-2004
- Anne LaBastille papers, 1963-2000
  - Fan Mail, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Fan Mail, 2000, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Critiques of Woodswoman by young students, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Critiques of Woodswoman by young students, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Book reports on Woodswoman by high school students, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - "My friend on Black Bear Lake," by Ryan Green, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Evaluations of presentation at Clinton-Essex Franklin Library, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Journal of Earthwise workshop participant, Sue Anne, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake: letter and editorial corrections, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - "Wood Woman Journals, by students at Delaware Academy", 1996 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Letters from Anne to Nancy Kroening, 1980-2004 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - "Christmas Verse", 1968 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    1 handwritten copy and 1 printed copy
  - Tomboys - Chapter in Jo's Girls - C. McEwen, January 1995 - August 1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Tomboys draft; correspondence with Christian McEwen
  - Society of Women Geographers Oral History Project - LaBastille, October 2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Transcript of interview
  - Contributed Book Chapters, 1990-1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Writing, Book Proposal, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - LaBastille Proposed Novel Rejected, November 1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Song by Anne "Autumn in the Adirondacks", July 17, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Sheet music; Ballard Park Concert Series program (premiere location)
  - Unpublished? - Possibly in Wilderness World Anne LaBastille includes critiques, 1986-2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Poetry 1940's-1960's, 1940s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - ALB Youth Writing, Photos approx. 7, 1940s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Story of Poodle - Scrapbook, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - New Essays on Walden: "Fishing in the Sky" Draft, April 24, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Cambridge University Press
  - "Web-foot your way to winter beauty" article, November 12, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Clipping from unknown publication
  - "Adventure in the Puerto Rican Rain Forest" Draft & Slides, December 8, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Includes letter from McIntosh & Otis, Inc.
  - Ride on Wild Side - Boston Globe, March 1993 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Published March 21, 1993; includes draft and slides
  - Today's Girl Annie Elbows, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Includes correspondence with Publishers Services Incorporated and West of the Wind Publication & draft of stories
  - The Wilderness World Book jacket, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript - Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille, 1975-1990 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript - Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - National Geographic, November 1981 (Box 9)
    Vol. 160, No. 5; LaBastille article "Acid Rain - How Great a Menace?" pg 652
  - National Geographic, January 1969 (Box 9)
    Vol. 135, No. 1; LaBastille Bowes article " The Quetzal" pg 141
  - National Geographic, May 1975 (Box 9)
    Vol. 147, No. 5; LaBastille article "My Backyard, the Adirondacks" pg 616
  - Ice Age Trail Notes, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Includes National Geographic Vol. 152, No. 2 in which article was published
  - "The Adirondacks, Forever Wild and Wondrous"article, November 1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Includes Reader's Digest issue November 1986
  - Cornell University related materials, 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Includes President's Council of Cornell Women certificate; Directory of Staff 1970-71; Summer at Cornell 1970 program; Cornell University Announcements: Education 1970-71
  - Scrapbook of Articles 1960s-1970s, 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
  - A Syllabus Describing Nature Center Operation and Programming, Direction and Development, July 1970 (Box 9)
    Prepared by Dr. Anne LaBastille
  - Birds of the Mayas covers, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    4 copies
  - Birds of Mayas, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence & Women and the Wilderness draft, 1980-1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Women and Wilderness slides, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    (last date noted: 1969)
  - Woodswoman IIII Photo albums, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    4 Volumes
  - Woodswoman III, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Includes Woodswoman III draft; book jacket proofs
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    New York: W. W. Norton & Company, Inc.
  - Beyond Black Bear Lake Layout, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Descriptions of photo layout in book
  - Woodswoman IIII Early Manuscripts, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    Anne LaBastille
  - Correspondence on Woodswoman IIII, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Includes prints of book jacket; notes on PCN
  - Woodswoman IIII Manuscript, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Woodswoman IIII Images and Cover, c. 2003; CD-2889-2890 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Woodswoman IIII - Layout, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Woodswoman IIII First Draft Handwritten Notes, Undated c. 2002 (Box 10)
    8 spiral-bound notebooks
  - Women and Wilderness - Uncorrected Proof, October 22, 1980 (Box 10)
    San Francisco: Sierra Club Books
  - Assignment: Wildlife - Uncorrected Proof, 1980 (Box 10)
    Anne LaBastille; New York: E.P. Dutton
  - Mama Poc manuscript (1), Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Mama Poc manuscript (2), Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Mama Poc (Spansich layout), Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Mama Poc - cover and masters, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Mama Poc - assignment wildlife photos, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Jaguar Totem book and cover, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Includes original Jaguar face slide
  - Jaguar Totem, Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Guatemala canoe accident, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Womman of the Woods", the Adirondack, vol 16, no. 31, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Jaguar Totem photos (ch. 5?), Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Book prints (Jaguar Totem?), Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - M.S. thesis negatives and slides, Undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Photos of Anne used in publication, 1986-06-17 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Drafts, correspondence, and published writings, 1984-2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Wisconsin pictures, Undated; National Geographic Society (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Binder of correspondence for publishing writings and photos, 1955-1963 (Box 13)
  - Caribbean wildlife tours notebooks, 1960-02-01-1963-02-25 (Box 13)
    Endorsed by Broward Audubon Society
  - Birthday card, 1998; 14x20 inches (Folder 1)
  - Uncut proof from The Wilderness World of Anne LaBastille (Folder 1)
    3 copies